Good Morning!
What a great and wonderful God we serve!
Our God is an awesome God.
We are serving a Living God;
to His power, nothing is impossible.
He is here in our midst today.
Greet Him. Say, "Thank You, Jesus!"
He is indeed the Living God.
Praise the Lord!
You may be seated. Have your seat in His presence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
My name is Racine.
I'm here today to share His message of salvation, in Jesus' name.
I say to you, "In Jesus' name".
God's Word is the key.
Let someone say, "God's Word is the key".
God has given us the way to abundant life.
The way to success, the way to good success is for you today.
So no matter what you face today,
I pray God gives you the grace to listen to this message.
This message I have received from the teaching of the man of God.
By the time you listen to this message and apply it,
you will know that the way out for you has come.
Say, "The way out for me has come".
Thank You, Jesus!
Brethren, there are many questionable conversions today.
Many are merely convinced but not yet converted.
You can know if one's conversion is questionable;
you can know when the man cannot act on the Word of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Mental assent recognises the truthfulness of the Word of God but cannot act on the Word.
There is a difference between knowing about God and knowing God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
One can be convinced that Jesus is the Son of God and still never find Jesus.
Say, "Neighbour, listen to the Word of God".
In His Word - salvation.
In His Word - deliverance.
Knowing the Holy Spirit is knowing God.
It is the Spirit of the Father who reveals God to us.
That is why we say, we are sons and daughters of God by revelation.
Say, "Neighbour, we are sons and daughters of God by revelation".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If one is serving God without the Holy Spirit, he is serving a god he does not know.
Say, "Neighbour, don't tell me what you feel.
Tell me what you know.
Tell me what you believe.
We are Christians by revelation".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "I am a Christian by revelation".
We act in the Word,
we do the Word,
we live in the Word
and we trust implicitly in the Word of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Acting on the Word of God makes Jesus truly real to the believer.
Acting on the Word of God gives God the opportunity to bless you,
to heal you, to deliver you and to save you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, we are Christians by revelation".
The Bible says, the Christian home - put your hand on your heart -
say, "The Christian home - that home is your heart.
The Christian home is the high school of learning whereby many truths are imbibed".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Holy Spirit is the Organ by which we apprehend spiritual things, spiritual truths.
This brings us to our message today: The Illumination of the Spirit.
Tell your neighbour, "The Illumination of the Spirit".
Say, "Neighbour, be illumined by the Spirit of God".
Turn your Bible with me to the Book of 2 Corinthians.
We start our reading from Chapter 4.
2 Corinthians 4.
I start from verse 6 to 7.
It reads:
"For it is the God who commanded the light to shine out of darkness, who has shone in our hearts
to give the light of the knowledge of the glory of God in the face of Jesus Christ."
Verse 7.
"But we have this treasure in earthen vessels,
that the excellence of the power may be of God and not of us."
Say, "Neighbour, the illumination of the Holy Spirit".
In the Book of Acts 19 - when you go home, you read from verse 1 to 6 -
Paul the Apostle visited the church at Ephesus
and he perceived that they were serving a god they did not know.
He asked them, "Did you receive the Holy Spirit when you believed?"
Because knowing Jesus is knowing the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
They answered, "We have never heard that there is a Holy Spirit".
Their worship was defective.
They knew all the rites but still they did not know Jesus.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When Paul began to preach the revealing Word of God, spiritual enlightenment came.
They acted on it and the saving power of God descended on them and they were saved
and they received the baptism in the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What can we say about that today?
Brethren, the Kingdom of Light, the Kingdom of God is not something hoped for or a mere wish;
it is a fact - it is a reality.
Jesus said in Luke 17:20-22 that the Kingdom of God does not come by observation or sight
but the Kingdom of God is within you.
Say, "Neighbour, the Kingdom of God, the Kingdom of Light is within you".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This means, the Kingdom of Light is in the Living Word within you.
Say, "Neighbour, the Kingdom of Light is in the Living Word within you".
You need to discover it.
We need to discover it.
The Scripture says, the great objects of faith are made known to us by divine revelation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How does that revelation come?
How does it come?
Ask the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua and he will tell you:
It is not all up to God and certainly, it is not all up to you; you have a role to play.
Say, "Neighbour, you have a role to play".
What is that role?
Me-di-ta-tion!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you ready for the journey?
Are you ready for the key to success?
Say, "Meditation brings revelation".
Meditation brings revelation.
Meditation in the Word of God is a visit with God.
It is when you meditate on the Word of God that the Word of God enters your heart - your spirit -
and when it does, our spirit acts on it and revelation comes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let someone say, "Meditation brings revelation".
The new revelation knowledge that comes from above comes by acting in the Word
and living in the Word.
Job 32:8 says that when the Holy Spirit begins to speak to our hearts,
revelation comes and changes are beginning.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The man of God says that revelation is the realisation of something not previously known.
Say, "Revelation is the realisation of something not previously known".
When you know it, you will know God's opinion about you and others.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Meditation brings revelation.
Revelation brings conviction.
Say, "Revelation brings conviction".
The Book of Romans 14:5 says, "Let everyone be convinced in his own mind".
You have heard so much about this ministry.
Many are here to see but the Bible says, "Let everyone be convinced in his own mind".
That I have the revelation that Jesus Christ of Nazareth is the Son of God,
the Saviour of the world, does not mean I can get you to believe the truth.
You must get that revelation yourself in order to believe because faith is a conviction.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let someone say, "Faith is a conviction".
It is a trust that arises in each person's heart, based on the Word of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is conviction?
The man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, says that
conviction is the awakening of man's conscience to the truth.
Say to yourself, "Conviction is the awakening of my conscience to the truth".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is truth?
The Scripture says to know the truth is to know Jesus Christ.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith in Christ Jesus is a trust that arises out of the fact that
God is reliable, trustworthy and steadfast.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
To trust means to believe the truth, to accept the truth
and be totally committed to that truth.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you do, nothing can change your mind about what you believe.
You will remain an agent of truth in the midst of lies.
You will remain an agent of faithfulness in the midst of unfaithfulness.
You will remain a channel of humility in the face of pride.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let someone say, "Revelation brings conviction".
This means, every time our spirit acts on the revealing Word of God,
something enters our spirit that increases our assurance - that is conviction.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, I am a child of God.
I am born again. I am justified. I am redeemed.
I am the righteousness of God in Christ Jesus.
It is the development of God's Word on the inside of you by meditation
that gives birth to belief in your heart.
Say, "Neighbour, it is the development of God's Word on the inside of me
that gives birth to belief in my heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Faith is my movement towards God".
Mediation in the Word is a visit with God.
The more you get closer to God by meditation,
the more you begin to sense His righteousness and holiness.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brethren, meditation brings revelation.
Revelation brings conviction.
Conviction brings real movement.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Conviction leads to a heart decision, which leads to real movement.
What do I mean by that?
The Bible says, when we move, power steps.
Say, "When I step, power steps - the power of God - with intent and purpose".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
How can this happen?
Let someone say, "God Almighty is with us in the Living Word".
Say, "Emmanuel!
God with me!
Emmanuel!
God with me!"
The Living God is with us in the Living Word.
This means, every step we take, we step in the presence of God.
Every look I take, I look with the power of God.
Every movement I take, I move with the Kingdom of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, when I move, power moves".
To stay with Jesus Christ of Nazareth is to stay with the Holy Spirit -
there lies our safety.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Meditation brings revelation.
Revelation brings conviction.
Conviction brings real movement.
Now to illustrate this process, let's go to the Bible.
In the Book of Acts 10:9-19, the Bible says there was a man called Cornelius.
He had a divine appointment with God -
a divine appointment with salvation, with righteousness of God
but God does nothing without His Word.
So, God chose Simon Peter to be the one to deliver the message of righteousness
to the household of Cornelius.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Peter, being a Jew, had no interaction with gentiles.
He never went to the house of a gentile, so God gave him a vision of revelation.
Read from verse 10 to 11.
God showed him all sorts of impure animals and said, "Peter, kill and eat".
Peter said, "Lord, I have never eaten anything impure".
God said, "Don't call impure what I call pure".
He resisted the vision three times because Peter could not understand the vision.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brethren, say, "Meditation brings revelation".
Verse 19 says when Peter was busy thinking over the vision, meditating on the vision,
the Bible says revelation came.
The Spirit of God spoke to him and said to him,
'Go with them; doubt nothing. I am the One that sent them'.
That meditation brought revelation;
that revelation brought to Peter conviction that this is the will of God.
Then, he took a real movement.
Peter stepped out with boldness and went to the house of Cornelius -
obedience to the Word of God.
The Bible says when he came, he preached the Word of salvation
and the power of God came on all the household.
And the Bible says they were saved.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What lesson can we learn from Peter's experience for us today?
No one can obey the written Word without the help of the Holy Spirit.
Human nature, the natural man, the man of the mind and intellect
cannot understand or receive the things of the Holy Ghost
because they are spiritually discerned.
So, our earthly understanding must give way to spiritual enlightenment.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Neighbour, I don't know what your problem is this morning.
I don't know what brought you today.
But all I know, God is still saying something.
No matter how dark your situation is, God is saying something!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Finally, brethren.
If our faith is to be a 'New Testament faith',
if Christ Jesus is to be the Christ of God rather than the Christ of history - baby Jesus,
then the illumination of the Spirit will tell in your heart
that you are learning at the feet of Jesus, not at the feet of man.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Christianity stands or falls on Jesus Christ of Nazareth.
Christianity stands or falls on the illumination of the Holy Spirit.
No one can say, "Jesus is Lord!" unless he is guided by the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, the way out for you has come.
Neighbour, the way to a successful prayer life has come.
The key to revelation has come.
The key to conviction has come.
The key to the step of faith has come".
No matter what you are experiencing here today, don't panic; run to God.
Run to God!
No matter how dark the situation you are experiencing today in your life,
home, business, career, engage your heart with God.
The Bible says if the answers to your prayers are not given, hold on and hold out
'til you receive revelation, understanding from God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say, "Neighbour, meditate 'til God Almighty gives you a clear light".
When the illumination of the Spirit comes into your life and situation,
you will know the power you are under.
You will know God's opinion about yourself and others.
You will know God's opinion on the matter, why God allowed the things to happen -
to bring a greater revelation in your life.
Meditation brings revelation; revelation brings results.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, brethren, this is my word.
Can you stand up in His presence.
Can you stand up in the presence of God.
Say, "I am a Christian by revelation.
I know I am serving the Living God.
You situation, trouble - you want to blacken, darken but let me tell you,
beyond that situation lies God's purpose for my life.
I know the way out for me has come.
Today, I am in the presence of the Almighty God.
You situation, I refuse to obey.
I know my God is greater than you".
Today, when you apply the message, mediation brings revelation.
Say, "God dwells in my heart.
Meditation brings conviction; conviction brings real movement.
I take a step of faith.
I will not draw back; I will move on and on because victory is mine!"
God bless His Word!
The SCOAN Sunday Service